Sometimes Dr. Lecter and I would talk...
有时在夜深人静的时候
when things got quiet enough...
汉尼伯医生会和我聊聊天
about the science courses I was takin'.
谈我所选修的科学课程
Some kind of mail-order courses in psychology, Nurse Barney?
那种邮购的心理学课程 也能称为科学？
No, sir.
当然不是
I don't consider psychology a science...
我并不认为心理学是科学
and neither did Dr. Lecter.
汉尼伯医生也不这么想
Now, Barney...
那么，巴尼…
while you were working at the asylum...
当你在收容所工作的时候
you observed Clarice Starling and Hannibal Lecter interacting.
你的确看到史达琳和 汉尼伯之间有互动关系
Interacting?
互动？
Talking to one another.
就是聊天之类的
Yes. Yes, it seemed to me that they...
是的，他们看起来好像是…
I can see you're eager to justify your consulting fee...
我知道你很想拿这笔咨询费
but why don't we start with what you saw...
但是只说你看到的
not what you thought about what you saw?
别把自己的想法加进去
Cordell, don't be like that. Barney can give us his opinion.
柯德，别这样 他当然可以表达自己的意见
Barney, give us your opinion of what you saw.
巴尼，告诉我们你的看法
What was it between them?
你觉得他们之间是哪种关系？
Most of the time, Dr. Lecter didn't respond at all to visitors.
通常汉尼伯医生 根本不理会来访的观察员
He'd just, for instance, open his eyes long enough...
甚至会不发一言的 瞪着前来观察的学生
to insult some academic who was there to look over him.
好让他们觉得难堪
With Starling, he answered her questions.
但是他却回答史达琳的问话
She interested him. She intrigued him.
她引起了他的兴趣 也被她深深的吸引住
He thought she was charming and amusing.
他认为她既迷人又有趣
So Clarice Starling and Hannibal Lecter...
所以史达琳和汉尼伯…
became friendly.
就变成了朋友
Inside a kind of formal structure, yes.
不错，是一种形而上的朋友
And he was fond of her.
这么说来他很喜欢她？
Yes.
是的
Thank you, Barney.
巴尼，谢谢你
Thank you very much for your candor.
谢谢你的坦白
And keep all those wonderful items...
至于你卖给我的那些…
from your personal Lecter treasure trove coming.
汉尼伯的珍贵收藏品
I've enjoyed them immensely.
我非常喜欢
Mr. Verger.
维杰先生
Oh, I almost forgot.
喔，我差点忘了
I might be able to get a cookie down. What do you say, Cordell?
柯德，我能吃块甜点吗？
I think it would kill you.
那会要了你的命
How much? Two hundred and fifty.
多少钱？      二十五…
Thousand.
万
Cut a check for $250,000.
去开张二十五万的支票
How can she sleep at a time like this?
这种时候她也能睡
She's on a jump-out squad all night. She's saving her strength.
她昨晚出勤，现在正养精蓄锐
We got some guy named Bolton from the DC Police.
听说从华府警局 来了个叫柏顿的家伙
All right, everyone. Pay attention. Here's the layout.
大家请注意，这是现场区域图
Excuse me. I'm Officer Bolton, DC Police.
抱歉，我是华府警探柏顿
I can see that from your badge. How do you do?
你好，从警徽上我可以看出来
I'm in charge here.
我是这里的负责人
Officer Bolton, I'm Special Agent Starling.
柏顿警探 我是史达琳探员
Just so we don't get off on the wrong foot...
为了避免不必要的误会
let me explain why we're all here.
让我解释一下我们来此的目的
I'm here because I know Evelda Drumgo. I arrested her twice on RICO warrants.
我对艾微达很了解 因为我曾逮捕过她两次
DEA and ATF, in addition to backing me up...
这次因为牵涉到毒品和枪械
are here for the drugs and the weapons.
禁药取缔局和武器管理局 也一起参加行动
You're here because our mayor wants to appear tough on drugs...
至于你来这里是因为 市长在被判了使用古柯碱罪后
especially after his own cocaine conviction...
为了表现出取缔毒品的决心
and hopes he can accomplish that by having you join us here today.
才让你们加入我们的行动
You got a smart mouth, lady.
小姐，你倒挺凶的嘛
If you wouldn't mind, I'd appreciate it if you'd let me continue.
如果你不介意 我们可以继续讨论吗？
All right, take a look.
好，大家看一下
Fish market. Back's on the water.
鲜鱼市场的后面是水
Across the street, ground floor, is the meth lab.
对面是毒品制造所
Evelda Drumgo's HIV positive.
“通缉犯” 艾微达是爱滋病患者
She will spit and bite if cornered, so you should watch it.
紧要关头她会又抓又咬 你们要小心
If you happen to be the one who puts her in a patrol car...
柏顿，万一是你在媒体前 送她进警车，千万别碰她的头
She'll likely have a needle in her hair.
因为她喜欢把针藏在头发里
We want to take her inside the building, not out in the street.
最好能在室内将她拿下 “公共市场”
We can get closest with the van.
大家尽量靠近我们的伪装车
If it looks good, on my signal we hit the front, DEA hits the back...
到时候我们从前面进攻 禁药组攻打后面
DCPD backin'them up.
请华府警探去支援禁药组
She'll have her watchers out at least three blocks around.
她的了望员会守在三条街前
They've tipped her before in time, so let's not make spectacles of ourselves.
以便及时给她消息 所以我们不要太招摇
Pretty busy today. I agree.
今天挺忙碌的   没错
Can I please get a cup of coffee?
请给我杯咖啡
Did you see that? That's a roger.
你看到了吗？ 那表示可以行动
What's up, man?
嘿，近来如何？
Goddamn it. It's her.
该死，她出来了
With three guys. They're all packin'.
有三个人，都带着枪
She's carryin' something. She's got a baby.
她胸前挂着东西，是婴儿
Hey, Brigham, it's too crowded.
柏汉，人太多
There are too many people. I say we call it off.
我看取消比较好
What do you say?
你说呢？
I agree.
我同意
All units, stand down.
所有单位，行动取消
Whiskey team copies. Burke copy.
威士基知道了 柏克知道了
This is Bolton. Stay on target.
这是柏顿，我要继续行动
I said all units stand down, Bolton, right now.
柏顿，我已说过取消行动
It's too late. We're movin'in. Bolton, he said it's off.
太晚了，我们已经开始 柏顿，请你合作
Stand down now.
不准行动
She's carrying a baby. I repeat, she's carrying a baby.
因为她胸前有婴儿 重复她有婴儿
All units stand down.
所有单位不要行动
Keep that gun down, Bolton. Damn, dude got a piece.
柏顿，把枪收起来 要命，有人拿枪
Light his ass up. It's a go!
先杀了他      快走！
FBI! Down on the ground!
调查局，快趴在地上
Hold it!
停火
Hold your fire!
不要开枪
Don't!
别开枪
Evelda, get out of the car!
艾微达，你出来
Starling, is that you?
是史达琳吗？
Step away from the car!
请你离开车子
Show me your hands, Evelda.
把手举起来
Please. Show me your hands.
请把手举起来
How've you been?
你近来好吗？
Don't do this.
别这样做
Do what?
做什么？
It's all right. It's okay.
好了，不会有事的
I know, I know. Baby, I know.
我知道，宝贝，你吓坏了
It's okay.
别哭
Friends, family and coworkers gathered here this morning...
今早朋友、家人和同事 聚集在阿灵顿国家公墓中
This ill-fated drug raid that claimed his life and five others...
这场毒品突击 夺去他及另外五个人的生命
is the latest in a seemingly endless series of incidents...
这一连串的意外事件 始于德州的瓦库
in which theJustice Department and the FBI have been questioned...
对于探员们只知使用武力 而不愿运用大脑一事
about their use of firepower rather than judgment.
司法部及调查局已受到质询
This time it was FBI Special Agent Clarice Starling...
这次的灾难是由调查局探员 史达琳所引起
Agent Starling attained some measure of celebrity ten years ago...
十年前，为了营救 前田纳西议员的女儿凯瑟琳
when she was given information by Dr. Hannibal "The Cannibal"Lecter...
史达琳曾经由“食人魔” 汉尼伯医生的协助，得以破案
daughter of the former US senator from Tennessee.
她因此而声名大噪
When she returns to work this week, she won't be so celebrated.
但是这个礼拜当她回复工作时 迎接她的不是表扬而是诉讼
Attorney Telford Higgins, representing one of the families of those slain...
因为代表被害家属的泰福律师 将控告她误杀至死之罪
Cordell!
柯德！
Yes, sir. Get me theJustice Department.
有什么吩咐 替我接司法部
Agent Starling?
史达琳探员
This is John Eldridge from DEA. Assistant Director Noonan, you know.
这是禁药取缔局的约翰 助理执政官诺门
Larkin Wayne from our Office of Professional Responsibility.
我们部门的拉金 他专精责任问题
Bob Sneed, ATF.
武器管制局的包勃
Benny Holcombe, assistant to the mayor. And Paul Krendler.
市长助理班尼 还有司法部的保罗
You know Paul. Paul's come over from Justice...
你应该认识他
unofficially, as a favor to us.
他以非官方身份来协助我们
In other words, he's here, and he's not here.
换句话说，他并不在这里
So I take it you've seen the coverage in the papers and on television?
我想你已经看过 报纸和电视的报导吧
I have nothing to do with the news, Mr. Krendler.
那些新闻和我无关
The woman had a baby in her arms.
那个女人手中抱着婴儿
There are pictures. You could see the problem, I would think.
照片就在这里 你应该知道问题有多严重
Not in her arms. In a carrier across her chest.
婴儿是在她胸前挂的婴儿袋里
In her arms she had a MAC-10.
她手里抱的是冲锋枪
Look, we're here to help you, Starling.
我们是来帮你的
It's gonna be a hell of a lot harder to do with a combative attitude.
你这样怒气冲冲的态度 只会使事情更难办
Can I speak freely, Mr. Pearsall?
我能自由发言吗？
Your agency called this office to get me assigned to help you on this raid.
我是应你们的要求 来协助做这次突击的
I tried to do that.
我的确尽力去做
I clearly expressed my judgment and was ignored.
但有人却不遵守我所做的判断
And now a good agent and a friend is dead.
以致牺牲了一位 好朋友也是好探员
You shot and killed five people out there, Agent Starling.
别忘了你还杀了五个人
Is that how you define good judgment?
难道能说这是好的判断吗？
This raid was an ugly mess.
这是一场丑恶的突击
I ended up in a position where I had a choice of dying...
我被迫在被杀
or shooting a woman carrying a child.
或射杀 身挂婴儿的女人中做选择
I chose.
我做了选择
I shot her.
就是射杀她
I killed a mother holding her child.
我杀了带着婴儿的母亲
And I regret it. I resent myself for it.
我很后悔，也恨我自己
Gentlemen, I'm going to call a halt to this meeting...
对不起，现在要终止这个会议
and get back to you individually by phone.
我会个别打电话给你们
That was a waste of time.
真会浪费时间
You have a secret admirer, Starling.
史达琳，你居然有秘密仰慕者
He isn't much to look at, but he does have friends in high places.
他本身不怎么样 却有身居高位的朋友
Remember Mason Verger?
你记得马森维杰吗？
Lecter's fourth victim.
汉尼伯的第四个被害人
The rich one.
他很富有
The only one that survived.
也是唯一死里逃生的人
He says he has some new information on Lecter he'll only share with you.
他说有些汉尼伯的新资料 但是只愿意告诉你
What do you mean, only share it with me? You want it, seize it.
那是什么意思？ 如有需要，就扣押文件呀
I'd rather not. I wasn't speaking to you.
最好别这么做 保罗先生，我并没有和你讲话
When I speak to you, you'll know it because I'll look at you.
当我和你讲话时 自然会看着你
Why would we rather not?
为什么不这么做？
The last time he called was when we took Lecter off the Ten Most Wanted List.
上次他因为我们把汉尼伯从 十大通缉犯中除去而打电话来
He was upset about that. We said, "Hey, that's life."
他很生气，我们对他说 “嘿，你最好接受”
to make your life miserable. "
会给你们好看的
His family's political contributions may not be enough...
他家族对政治上献金一向慷慨
to buy a senator...
虽然买不起参议员
but they are enough to rent them from time to time.
但是绝对租得起
There's no reason to go through that if he really does have something new.
况且他若真有线索 我们又何必惹他生气
It's a good deal for you, Starling. You can't pretend it isn't.
史达琳，其实这件事对你有利
Get to go back on a celebrated case.
因为你能再回去侦办知名案件
I'll take care of the media for your Drumgo killing.
媒体方面 我会替你去和他们交涉
Everyone's gonna be happy.
大家都高兴
I'm not happy.
我并不高兴
Well, maybe you're incapable of being happy.
也许你根本就不会高兴
Mr. Krendler...
保罗先生
out on the street, you know you might take a bullet in the line of duty.
我们都知道做为一个探员 随时都有死亡的危险
You accept it or you get out.
如果怕死，那就不要做
You live with it.
所以我们接受这个事实
What you don't expect or accept...
但所不能接受的是
is taking one in the back in your boss's office...
你按照所受过的训练 和上级的指示去做
for doing your job exactly as they've taught you.
而结果却背上黑锅
That makes you unhappy.
这才叫人气愤
Of course you're right, Starling...
史达琳，你说得不错
but it doesn't change anything.
但毕竟改变不了什么
It changes everything. It changes me.
它改变了一切，连我在内
Hi, I'm Cordell Doemling, Mr. Verger's private physician.
嗨，我叫柯德 是维杰先生的私人医生
How do you do?
你好
If you'd be so kind as to park down at the end.
麻烦你把车停到那边
One's eyes adjust to the darkness.
眼睛会随着光线而调整
Mr. Verger, Agent Starling is here.
维杰先生，史达琳探员来了
Good morning, Mr. Verger.
你早，维杰先生
Was that a Mustang I heard out there?
你开的是福特野马吗？
Yes, it was.
是的
Five-liter?
5000c.c.的引擎？
Fast.
那好快呀
Cordell, I think you can leave us now.
柯德，你可以离开了
I thought I might stay. Perhaps I could be useful.
如果我留下来可能会有用
You could be useful seeing about my lunch.
你去看我的午餐准备得如何
I'll attach this microphone to your clothing or pillow, if that's okay.
你不介意我把麦克风 夹在你的衣服或枕头上吧
By all means.
不会的
Here, this should make it easier.
这样会比较容易些
You know, I thank God...
对发生在我身上的事
for what happened.
我必须感谢上帝
It was my salvation.
因为这是赎罪
Have you accepted Jesus, Agent Starling?
史达琳探员，你信主吗？
Do you have faith? I was raised Lutheran.
你有信仰吗？ 我家人信奉路德教派
That's not what I asked.
那不是我问的问题
This is Special Agent Clarice Starling, 5143690...
这是5143690号史达琳探员
deposing Mason R. Verger on March 20, sworn and attested.
我作证在三月二十日 维杰已经发誓会说实话
I want to tell you about summer camp. It was a wonderful childhood experience.
我想说我童年时代 在夏令营里的快乐时光
We can get to that later. We can get to it now.
等会儿再谈吧 我现在就要说
You see, it all comes to bear.
因为这些全有关联
It was a Christian camp my father founded...
那是在我父亲所创办的 基督夏令营里
for poor, unfortunate, cast-off little boys and girls...
它专门收容 孤苦无依的孩子们
who would do anything for a candy bar.
为了一块糖，他们愿做任何事
Mr. Verger, I don't need to know about the sex offenses.
维杰先生 我对你的恋童癖不感兴趣
It's all right. I have immunity from the US Attorney.
没关系 在美国律师之前我已免疫
And I have immunity...
甚至在上帝面前…
from the risen Jesus.
我也免疫了
And nobody beats the Riz.
因为没人禁得起 巧克力糖的诱惑
Had you ever seen Dr. Lecter before the court assigned you to him for therapy?
在法院指派汉尼伯医生给你前 你是否已经认识他？
What do you mean?
你指的是…
Socially?
社交上的认识？
It is what I mean, yes, if you don't mind talking about it.
是的，你介意谈论它吗？
No, not at all. I'm not ashamed.
不会，我并不引以为耻
I didn't say you should be. No, we met conventionally...
我没这么说 我们认识得很平常
as doctor and patient.
是医师和病人的关系
How did he end up at your house?
那他怎么会到你住处去？
I invited him, of course...
当然是我邀他的啰
to my pied-a-terre.
我邀他到我的临时住所去
I came to the door in my nicest come-hither outfit.
我穿着最诱人的衣服去开门
I was concerned...
因为我担心…
that he'd be afraid of me.
他可能会怕我
But he didn't seem to be afraid of me.
但他似乎一点也不在乎
That's almost funny now.
现在想起来是很可疑
I showed him my toys...
我把我的性玩具拿给他看
my noose setup, among other things.
其中包括那套活结装置
It's where you sort of hang yourself, but not really.
就是可以把自己吊起来 却又不会窒息的装置
It feels good while you...
那种感觉真好，如果…
well, you know.
反正你能想像得出来
Anyway...
总归…
he said, "Mason..." Mason, would you like a popper?
他说“维杰…” 维杰，要不要来点兴奋剂？
And I said, "Would I? Oh, wow!"
我说“哇！当然要”
Once that kicked in, I was flying.
等药效出来后，我高到极点
He said, "Mason, show me how you smile...
他说“让我看看你那种”
to gain the confidence of a child. "
“能赢得小孩信任的笑容”
When I smiled...
当我笑起来时…
he said, "Oh, I see how you do it."
他又说“我看出来 他们为什么会信任你”
The good doctor approached me with a piece of broken mirror.
医生手里拿着 镜子的碎片朝我走来
"Try this."
“试试用这个”
Try peeling off your face...
把你脸上的肉割下来
And feeding it to the dogs.
然后拿去喂狗吃
No, I can still see it.
不行，我还是看得到你的笑容
Try again.
再来一次
No, I'm afraid not.
还是不行
That's entertainment
那就是所谓的娱乐
Well, it seemed like a good idea at the time.
说实话，当时似乎觉得很好玩
Where did this come from?
这是怎么来的？
Buenos Aires. I received it two weeks ago.
寄来的，两个星期前到的
Where's the package it came in?
外面的信封呢？
Good question. There was nothing written on it of interest.
问得好 上面并没有写什么重要的东西
Did we throw it out?
我们是不是扔了？
Yes, I'm afraid we did.
是的，实在很抱歉
Oh, dear. You think it'll help?
你看这个会有帮助吗？
I hope so.
但愿如此
I hope it'll help you catch him...
希望能帮你捉到他
to help cleanse the stigma of your recent dishonor.
以雪你这次不名誉的耻辱
Thank you. That's all I need.
谢谢你，我走了
Did you find some rapport with Dr. Lecter...
当你在收容所 和汉尼伯医生谈话时
in your talks at the asylum?
有没有对他产生信赖感？
I know I did while I was peeling.
当我在割自己脸时 曾经有过那种感觉
We exchanged information in a civil way.
我们是用文明的方法交换心得
But always through the glass.
但还是隔着一层玻璃
Yes.
是的
Isn't it funny? What's that?
你很奇怪   为什么？
You can look at my face...
你对我的脸无动于衷
but you shied when I said the name of God.
可是一听我提上帝 反儿使你胆怯
Finding what you want? Are you sure this is all of it?
找到你要找的吗？ 你确定只有这些
That's all there is now.
到目前为止，只剩这些
There was more, but it's been picked over little by little over the years.
本来不止的 可惜被人一点一点的拿走了
You know, this stuff's worth a lot of money in certain circles.
这些东西在特定市场中 能值不少钱
It's kind of like the cocaine that disappears around here...
就像这里的古柯碱一样
little by little.
一点一点的消失掉
Hey, Barney.
嘿，巴尼
Remember me?
还记得我吗？
Would you agree for the record, Agent Starling...
史达琳探员，请你声明 你并没有把权益念给我听
I have not Mirandized Barney. He is unaware of his rights.
我声明巴尼并不知道他的权益
So when you turned Dr. Lecter over to the Tennessee police...
在你把汉尼伯医生 交给田纳西警局后
They weren't civil to him. They're all dead now.
他们对他无礼，如今都死了
They only survived his company three days.
实际上他们只活了三天
You survived him six years at the asylum.
但是你却活了六年
How'd you do that? It wasn't just being civil.
你是怎么做到的？ 我觉得这和礼貌无关
Yes, it was.
有很大的关系
Did you ever think, after he escaped, he might come after you?
在他逃走后 你有没有想过他可能来找你？
No.
没有
He once told me that, whenever feasible...
他曾对我说过在可能的情况下
he preferred to eat the rude.
他宁愿吃无礼之人
"Free-range rude," he called 'em. What about you?
他叫他们“无礼鼠类” 你呢？
You ever think he might come after you? You ever think about him at all?
你有没有想过他 或想过他可能会来找你？
At least 30 seconds of every day. I can't help it.
每天都会想上三十秒
He's always with me, like a bad habit.
就像坏习惯一样，戒也戒不掉
Do you know what happened to his stuff... his books, papers, drawings?
他的东西，像书、纸 和图画等等都到哪里去了
Everything got thrown away when the place closed.
收容所关闭时 所有的东西都丢了
Cutbacks.
节省经费嘛
I just found out that Dr. Lecter's signed copy of TheJoy of Cooking...
我发现由汉尼伯医生 签名的那本烹饪之乐杂志
sold to a private collector for $16,000.
最近被私人收藏家 以一万六千美金买进
It was probably a fake.
恐怕是仿造品
The seller's affidavit of ownership was signed "Karen Phlox."
卖主切结书上的签名是 “费凯伦”
Do you know Karen Phlox? You should.
你应该认识她
She filled out your employment application, but signed it "Barney."
她曾替你填过工作申请表 最后签上“巴尼”
Same thing on your tax returns.
还有退税单也一样
You want the book? Maybe I can get it back.
如果你要书 我会试着把它要回来
I want the x-ray of Lecter's arm you broke in the attack on that nurse...
当他攻击护士时，你曾打断 他的手臂，我要那张X光片
and everything else you've got.
还有其它被你拿走的东西
We used to talk about a lot of things at night...
在夜深人静，尖叫声平息之后
after the screamin' finally died down.
我们时常聊天
We talked about you sometimes. You wanna know what he said?
有时也谈到你 你想知道他都说些什么吗？
Go get the x-ray.
把X光片给我
I'm not a bad guy.
我不是个坏人
I didn't say you were.
我没说你是坏人
Dr. Chilton was a bad guy.
奇顿医生才是坏人
After your first visit, he started taping your conversations with Lecter.
在你第一次访问汉尼伯医生后 他就开始录你们的谈话
These are valuable.
它们非常有价值
Go on now.
你走吧
You've grieved long enough.
你已经哀吊得够久了
And what'd he say?
他是怎么说的？
What'd he say about me late at night?
在晚上他怎么说我的？
He was talking about inherited, hardwired behavior.
他谈到遗传和内心深处的行为
He was using genetics in the roller pigeons as an example.
他用鹞鸽的遗传来做比方
They fly up in the air, roll backwards in a display, fallin' to the ground.
它们喜欢高高的飞到天上 然后炫耀的翻着筋斗俯冲下来
There are shallow rollers, and there are deep rollers.
鹞鸽分为肤浅和深沉两种
You can't breed two deep rollers...
但是当两只深沉鹞鸽结合后
or their young, their offspring, will roll all the way down...
它们的后代往往会
hit and die.
俯冲撞地而死
Agent Starling is a deep roller, Barney.
巴尼 史达琳探员是只深沉的鹞鸽
Let us hope one of her parents was not.
只希望她父母中有一个 是只肤浅的鹞鸽
Surely the odd confluence of events hasn't escaped you, Clarice.
你并没有离开正轨
Jack Crawford dangles you in front of me...
因为杰克在我面前向你挑战
then I give you a bit of help.
所以我才给你一些帮助
Do you think it's because I like to look at you...
难道你以为是因为…
and imagine how good you would taste...
我喜欢边看你 边想着你会有多可口吗？
Clarice?
真是这样吗？
I don't know. Is it?
我不知道，难道是真的？
I've been in this room for eight years now, Clarice.
我待在这个房间里已经八年
I know they will never, ever let me out while I'm alive.
我知道在我有生之年 他们是不会让我出去的
What I want is a view.
我只想能看外面的风景
I want a window where I can see a tree or even water.
给我一扇窗户 让我能看到树甚至河流
I want to be in a federal institution far away from Dr. Chilton.
我想转到联邦收容所去 那样才能远离奇顿医生
The Capponi correspondence goes back to the 13th century.
卡波尼图书馆中的书信 可以追溯到十三世纪
Dr. Fell might hold in his hand...
至于在费尔博士手中
his non-Italian hand...
他那非意大利人的手中
a note from Dante Alighieri himself.
很可能握有但丁的真迹
But would he recognize it? I think not.
但是他能分辨出真伪吗？ 我不认为
Gentlemen, you have examined him in medieval Italian...
各位，你们已经肯定 他对意大利中叶的辨认能力
and I will not deny that his language is admirable...
我也承认对一个外国人来说
for a straniero.
他的文字实在美妙
But is he acquainted with the personalities...
但是他是否真正具有 文艺复兴前佛罗伦斯的气质
I think not.
我却有所怀疑
What if he came upon a note in the Capponi library...
说不定哪天在卡波尼图书馆中
say from Guido di Cavalcanti?
他会声称找到了 诗人卡瓦澄第的真迹
Would he recognize that? I think not.
难道他真能分辨出真伪吗？ 我不相信
They're still arguing?
他们还在争论吗？
Sogliato wants the job for his nephew.
苏立想让他侄子做这份工作
But the scholars seem satisfied with the temporary guy they appointed.
可是学者们似乎对 他们所指定的人很满意
If he's such an expert on Dante...
倘若他真那么精通但丁
let him lecture on Dante to the Studiolo.
为何不让他 发表一场对但丁研究的演讲
Let him face them if he can. I look forward to it.
好面对但丁的爱好者 好主意
Very well. On the 14th.
那就订在十四号好了
Dr. Fell?
费尔博士吗？
Chief Inspector Rinaldo Pazzi of the questura.
我叫帕齐 是警察总部的督察
Commendatore, how can I be of service?
督察，我能帮什么忙？
Sorry. I'm investigating the disappearance...
抱歉，我在调查前任馆长 辛诺的失踪案件
I was wondering if... "Predecessor" implies I have the job.
不知道是否… 你这么说，好像我已做了馆长
Unfortunately, I don't. Not yet, though I am hopeful.
我是希望如此 可惜他们还没决定
They are letting me look after the library for a stipend.
他们只是支薪给我 让我照顾图书馆而已
The officers who first checked...
以前的调查员
didn't find any sort of farewell or suicide note.
没有找到遗书或自杀信
I was wondering if you...
希望你能…
If I come across anything in the Capponi library stuffed in a drawer or book...
如果我在抽屉或书中 找到任何有用的东西
I'll call you at once.
一定会立刻通知你
Thank you.
谢谢你
You've been reassigned.
你被改派任务了
Pardon?
你说什么？
You were on the II Mostro case, I'm sure I read.
我记得 你本来在调查莫斯楚的案件
Yes, that's right. Now you're on this.
没错   现在却查这个案子
This is much less grand a case, I would think.
就我所知，这不是什么大案子
Well, if I thought of my work in those terms...
如果以知名度而言…
yes, I guess I'd agree.
你说的不错
A missing person. Sorry?
调查失踪人口 你说什么？
Were you unfairly dismissed from the grander case, or did you deserve it?
是因为不平等待遇 还是因为你的能力不够？
Regarding this one, Dr. Fell...
费尔博士，让我们再回到原题
are the signore's personal effects still at the Palazzo?
辛诺的私人物品 是否仍在图书馆内？
Packed neatly in four cases with an inventory.
一共装了四大箱，还有清单
Alas, no note.
就是没有遗书
I'll send someone over to pick them up. Thank you for your help.
我会叫人来取，谢谢你的帮忙
Hey, thanks.
嘿，谢谢你
How's it going? Any leads?
进行的如何？有线索吗？
Yeah, they're all leads. They just don't lead to him.
都是线索，可惜就是找不到他
I don't know how you live with this stuff.
真佩服你能天天和这些为伍
Oh, God.
天呀
This is from the Guinness Book of World Records congratulating me...
这封是世界记录给我的恭贺函
on being the female FBI agent who has shot and killed the most people.
说我创下 女调查员中杀人最多的记录
Would you excuse me, please?
能不能请你离开一下
Sure.
没问题
Dear Clarice...
亲爱的史达琳
I've followed with enthusiasm the course of your disgrace and public shaming.
我认真追踪你这次的受辱事件
My own never bothered me except for the inconvenience...
我对自己的受辱并不在乎
of being incarcerated.
只对失去自由有所不满
But you may lack perspective.
但你的眼界，却让我操心
In our discussions down in the dungeon...
从我们在地牢中的讨论中
it was apparent to me that your father, the dead night watchman...
我发现 你那位做守夜员的父亲
figures largely in your value system.
在你心目中占有很重的份量
I think your success in putting an end toJame Gumb's career as a couturier...
当初你最得意 能将杰姆绳之以法
pleased you most because you could imagine your father being pleased.
因为你觉得 那会使你父亲引以为傲
But now, alas, you're in bad odor with the FBI.
可惜如今你却成了 调查局中的老鼠屎
Do you imagine your daddy being shamed by your disgrace?
“调查局探员枪杀五人” 你父亲会不会因此
Do you see him in his plain pine box...
而感到丢脸
the sorry, petty end of a promising career?
而痛心疾首吗？
What is worst about this humiliation, Clarice?
这份耻辱最大的影响是什么？
Is it how your failure will reflect on your mommy and daddy?
是因为你的失败 会影响到你父母的形象？
Is your worst fear that people will now and forever believe...
还是你害怕从此以后…
they were indeed just good old trailer-camp...
人们认为他们只是 住在活动房屋中…
tornado-bait white trash...
没用的穷白鬼
and that perhaps you are too?
而你也和他们一样？
By the way, I couldn't help noticing on the FBI's rather dull web site...
顺便一提 我发现在调查局的网页上
that I've been hoisted from the Bureau's archives of the common criminal...
我居然从普通罪犯
and elevated to the more prestigious Ten Most Wanted List.
升级到十大通缉犯
Is this coincidence, or are you back on the case?
是巧合 还是你又开始侦办我的案件？
If so, goody goody, because I need to come out of retirement...
果真如此，那好 我将从退隐的地方走出
and return to public life.
再回到公众的生活中去
I imagine you sitting in a dark basement room...
我可以想像出 你正坐在黯淡的地下室里
bent over papers and computer screens.
埋首于纸堆和电脑萤光幕中
Is that accurate?
我说对了吧
Please tell me truly, Special Agent Starling.
史达琳探员，请告诉我实话
Regards, your old pal, Hannibal Lecter, MD.
请珍重，你的老友 汉尼伯医生
PS: : Clearly this new assignment is not your choice.
附注：我看得出 这不是你的本意
Rather, I suppose, it is part of the bargain.
可能是某种交换
But you accepted it, Clarice.
可是你仍然接受了
Yourjob is to craft my doom...
你的职责是毁灭我
so I'm not sure how well I should wish you...
所以实在不知道 在信尾该怎么祝你
but I'm sure we'll have a lot of fun.
不过我相信 我们将会有很多乐趣
Ta-ta.
回见
"H."
“汉”
On the letter...
在信上…
there's one partial fingerprint here.
找到一个局部的指纹
Not enough to hold up in court. I know it's him.
可是在法庭上还嫌不够 这一定是他
Where he was when he wrote it is what I need.
我只想知道他在哪里写这封信
Well, the paper isn't gonna help.
可惜从信纸上看不出来
Yes, it's linen fibre, yes, it's on the expensive side...
其中有亚麻纤维的成份 应该属于奢侈品
but it's not so rare that you won't find it in a thousand stationery stores...
但是却不罕见，全球至少 有上千家店会卖这种信纸
It's the same with the ink, and the same with the wax.
至于墨水和腊也是一样
And your Las Vegas postmark?
还有拉斯维加斯的邮戳
You can check it out, but I'll bet you it came from a remailing service.
我跟你打赌 是由重寄邮件服务公司寄的
Las Vegas would be the last place he'd be.
看来赌城是他最后的停留点
It'd be an assault on his sense of taste.
他的品味不该这么低
Don't you feel eyes moving over your body, Clarice?
难道你不觉得 有目光在你身上游动吗？
I hardly see how you couldn't.
你当然会感觉得到
And don't your eyes move over the things you want?
人的眼光 会在喜欢的东西上游走
All right, then. Tell me how.
告诉我是怎么回事
No.
不
It's your turn to tell me, Clarice.
现在轮到你告诉我了
You don't have any more vacations to sell on Anthrax Island.
难道你想再骗我到那个 布满动物传染病的岛上去？
Quid pro quo, Clarice.
别忘了我们这是公平交易
I tell you things, you tell me things.
我告诉你一件事 你也得告诉我一件事
Not about this case. About yourself.
不谈案子，就说你自己吧
Quid pro quo.
这就是公平交易
Yes or no, Clarice?
史达琳，你愿意吗？
Hand cream.
手霜
Raw ambergris base.
其中有龙涎香
Tennessee lavender.
田纳西的薰衣草
Trace of something else.
还有一些别的东西
Fleece.
羊毛
Lovely.
不错
What's ambergris? Ambergris is a whale product.
龙涎香是什么东西？ 它来自鲸鱼
Alas, much as we'd like to, we can't import it.
虽然我们也喜欢但不准进口
Endangered Species Act.
因为这会危害到稀有动物
Where isn't it illegal? Japan, of course.
在哪些国家是合法呢？ 毫无疑问的是日本
Couple of places in Europe.
另外还有一些欧洲国家
You'd almost certainly find it somewhere in Paris...
我肯定在巴黎、罗马 阿姆斯特丹可以找到
Maybe London.
伦敦也有可能
This bouquet was hand-engineered to someone's specifications.
这种香味 是照客人的指示以手工合成的
Is there a way of knowing which shops? Of course. We'll give you a list.
能知道是出自哪个商店吗？ 可以，我们会给你一张名单
It'll be short.
放心，不会太长
I need opera tickets.
我需要歌剧票
I don't think I got any on me.
我身上没有了
It's sold out, whatever it's called.
换句话说是卖光了
It's the pretty, young wife with the ever-open beak who needs opera tickets.
是他那个年轻漂亮的太太 吵着要去看歌剧
Benetti. What?
班尼第   什么事？
Rewind it.
倒带
I can't rewind it. I'm making a copy. I'm recording.
不行，我正在拷贝
What is this?
这是什么带子？
Security camera from a perfume shop in Via Della Scala.
是位在斯卡拉大道上 香水店的防盗录影带
FBI, through Interpol, requested a copy.
美国调查局经由国际刑警组 向我们要求的
Why? They didn't say.
为什么？   他们没说
They didn't say? No. It was actually kind of weird.
没说？ 他们的态度很奇怪
They were making a point not to say.
摆明了不告诉我们
Are we going to the opera? Yes.
我们仍要去听歌剧吗？ 是的
Sorry. Yes, we are going.
对不起，当然要去
You got tickets?
买到票了吗？
No, but I will. In fact, I was just about to look here.
还没有，我正要上网查看 一定会买到
Please, not the back row. I would like to see it this time.
拜托别买得太后面 否则又看不到
Nowhere near the back row...
绝对不会
no matter what the cost.
这次不管多贵也要买前座
Tell me, Clarice, would you want to harm...
史达琳，你有没有想过
those who forced you to consider it, though?
去伤害那些迫害过你的人？
It's perfectly okay to admit it.
你尽管承认
It's perfectly au naturel...
因为想向敌人挑战
to want to taste the enemy.
那是人性自然的表现
It just feels so good. Tell me, Clarice.
它会使你感到愉快
What is your worst memory of childhood?
什么是你童年中 最不快乐的记忆？
Jesus, Starling! Can I help you, Mr. Krendler?
你吓了我一大跳 需要我帮忙吗？
What are you doing sitting there in the dark?
一个人坐在黑暗中干什么？
Thinking about cannibalism.
正想着吃人的问题
People in Justice are thinking too. You know that?
司法部也在思索这个问题 你知道吗？
They're thinking, "What exactly is she doing about Lecter?"
他们在想“她到底想对 汉尼伯采取什么手段”
Aren't you curious why he dines on his victims?
你对他爱吃人是否感到好奇？
What's the point of that?
这话是什么意思？
Are you writing a book or are you catching a crook?
你到底是想写小说 还是想捉贼？
To show his contempt for those who exasperate him.
为了报复那些侮辱他的人
Or sometimes to perform a public service.
所以他才偶尔充当刽子手
In the case of the flutist, Benjamin Raspail...
就拿横笛手班哲明为例
he did it to improve the sound of the Baltimore Philharmonic Orchestra...
由于他供应小牛胰脏 和七百美金一瓶的蒙哈榭白酒
serving the not-so-talented flute player's sweetbreads to the board...
给乐团中那些 没什么天份的横笛手享用
with a nice Montrachet at $700 a bottle.
因而使 巴尔的摩交响乐团的声名大噪
Wow.
哇！
That meal began with green oysters from the Gironde...
那顿饭的开胃菜是 产自法国隆特的牡蛎
followed by the sweetbreads, a sorbet...
接着是小牛胰脏、果汁奶冻
and then you can read here in Gourmet Cuisine: :
其他的你可以看这本美食杂志
"A notable dark and glossy ragout, the constituents never determined."
有名的黑且光泽的 蔬菜炖肉，其中材料不明”
I always figured him for a queer.
我一直认为他有同性恋
Why would you say that, Paul?
为什么你会这么想？
All this artsy-fartsy stuff.
因为他搞的 全是艺术方面的事
Chamber music, tea-party food. Not that I mean anything personal...
像音乐室、茶会美食之类的 不是我多事…
if you've got a lot of sympathy for those people.
我觉得你似乎很同情那种人
What I came to impress upon you, Starling...
我来这里是想让你明白
is I better see cooperation.
最好乖乖合作
There are no little fiefdoms here.
这案子不是你一个人的
I want to be copied on every 302, you understand?
你必须随时向我报告进展 懂吗？
If you work with me...
好好和我合作
then your so-called career here might improve.
那么你所谓的前途就会无量
If you don't, then all I have to do...
否则 我不但不在你名字下划线
is draw a line through your name rather than under it...
反而把线从你名字中间划过去
and it's over.
那你就前途无亮啦
Paul, what is it with you?
你到底想怎么样？
I told you to go home to your wife. That was wrong?
我叫你回到你太太身边去 难道错了吗？
What? Don't flatter yourself, Starling.
拜托，你少自做多情了
That was a long time ago.
那是几百年前的事
Why would I hold that against you?
我才不会记那么久的仇
And besides...
加上…
this town is full of corn pone, country pussy.
这个城里到处都是 种田的乡下女人
That said...
换句话说…
I wouldn't mind having a go with you right now, if you want to reconsider.
如果你愿意，我现在就能奉陪
In the gym, anytime. No pads.
我随时在拳击场候教 来场不穿保护衣的对打
Is it possible it went out with the regular mail?
会不会是用普通邮件送出的？
No, I overnighted it to you. I filled out the slip myself.
不会，是我亲手填的快递单
This was the day after your request.
而且在你委托的第二天就寄了
I did it right away. I don't understand what happened.
我实在想不通
You should have it by now.
你现在该收到了
I don't. Can you send me another one?
还没有 能不能请你再寄一份
Sure, I'll make another copy especially for you.
没问题 我会特别替你再录一份
Agent Clarice? Is that right? Can I call you Clarice?
是克莉丝探员吗？ 我能叫你克莉丝吗？
Agent Starling.
请叫我史达琳探员
I'd appreciate it. What's your name?
谢谢你的帮忙，请问贵姓？
My name is Franco Benetti.
我叫班尼帝
Agent Franco Benetti.
班尼帝探员
Thank you very much, Agent Benetti. Okay.
非常谢谢你，班尼帝探员 不客气
So I'll send you tomorrow? All right.
那我明天就寄给你 好的
Bye-bye.
再见
Nothin', huh?
还是没有线索？
Nothin' yet. Still waitin' on Florence and London.
没有，我还在等 佛罗伦斯和伦敦的录影带
The number you have dialed is not in service at this time.
你所拨的号码已停止使用
Please check the number...
请检查所拨的号码…
Yes?
什么事？
I have information about Hannibal Lecter.
我有汉尼伯的消息
Have you shared your information with the police, sir?
请问你是否和警方联络过？
I'm required to encourage you to do so.
我鼓励你先这么做
Is the reward payable under special circumstances?
在哪种情况下才会付悬赏金
May I suggest you contact an attorney...
我建议你在采取行动之前
before taking any possibly illegal action?
先和律师联络一下
There's one in Geneva who's excellent in these matters.
在日内瓦有个律师 专精这种案件
May I give you his toll-free number?
我可以给你他的免费电话
The number is 004123317.
号码是004123317
Thank you for calling.
谢谢你打电话过来
Yes. I was just speaking with someone who suggested...
有人向我建议…
There's a $ 100,000 advance.
预付金是十万美金
To qualify for the advance...
为了符合预付金的条件
a fingerprint must be provided, in situ, on an object.
必须先提供目标物的真实指纹
Once the print has been positively identified...
等身份证实无误后
the balance of the money will be placed in escrow...
即将余款存入瑞士银行
at Geneve Credit Suisse...
交由代书保管
and may be viewed at any time subject to 24-hour prior notification.
你可以随时检验 只要在24小时前通知即可
To repeat the message in French, press two.
听法文请按二
In Spanish, press three. In German...
西班牙文请按三，德文…
Dr. Fell, it's Inspector Pazzi.
费尔博士，我是帕齐督察
Yes, I can see you.
是的，我看得见你
Come on up.
请上来
Dr. Fell?
费尔博士？
Snap.
照张相
I should have encouraged you to bring someone along.
我应该嘱咐你多带个人来
The cases are on the heavy side.
箱子很重
Maybe you could help me with them.
也许要请你帮忙
Just down the stairs, I mean.
只要搬到楼下就好
Yeah.
好的
This way.
这边走
Here we are.
就在这儿
Is that the inventory? Yes.
那是清单吗？   是的
May I see it? Of course.
我能看吗？   当然可以
You are a Pazzi of the Pazzi family, I think.
你应该是帕齐家族之后
Wasn't it at the Palazzo Vecchio your ancestor was hanged?
在维琪奥王宫被吊死的 就是你的祖先
Francesco de' Pazzi.
他叫范斯库帕齐
Yes, thrown naked with a noose around his neck from a window.
脖子上绑着套索 裸体从窗口中被抛出去
Writhing and kicking alongside the archbishop...
在大主教的身边
against the cold stone wall.
碰撞着冰冷的墙壁 全身扭动挣扎而死
In fact, I found a very nice rendering of it...
前几天，我在图书馆中
here in the library the other day.
找到了相关的艺术文献
If you like, perhaps I could sneak it out for you.
如果你喜欢 我可以偷偷给你
I would think that might jeopardize your chances...
这么做的话…
for permanent appointment to the curatorship.
可能会影响到你做馆长的机会
Only if you told.
除非你去告密
Remind me... what was his crime?
他到底犯了什么罪？
He was accused of killing Giuliano de' Medici.
他被控杀死朱利亚诺梅迪奇
Unjustly?
不公正吗？
No, I don't think so.
不，应该是公正的
Then he wasn't just accused. He did it. He was guilty.
那么说来，他是罪有应得
I think that would make living in Florence with the name Pazzi...
我想就算在五百年后的今天
uncomfortable, even 500 years later.
你仍会为 祖先的罪行而感到困扰
Not really.
这倒不会
In fact, I can't remember the last time...
其实在今天之前
before today...
除了你…根本就没人提过
People don't always tell you what they're thinking.
通常人们 不会把他的想法说出来
They just see to it you don't...
只是会确实做到
advance in life.
不让你出人头地而已
I'm sorry, Commendatore.
对不起，请别介意
I too often say what I'm thinking.
我常想什么，就说什么
I'll be right back to help you.
我马上就回来帮你搬
You know, the room you're standing in was built in the 15th century.
你所待的房间 是建造在十五世纪
It's beautiful.
很美！
Yes, it is.
的确不错
Unfortunately, I think...
只可惜，我在想…
the heating system was installed about the same time.
暖气系统 可能也是那时候建造的
That's a pity. Yes.
那真不幸      的确
Okeydokey. Let's drag these down.
好吧，咱们把它们拿下去
Must be as heavy as bodies.
这大概和尸体一样重
And the set? Eight thousand.
这一套多少钱？ 八千里拉
Okay.
好
Hey, how much is this?
喂，这个要多少钱？
Fifty thousand. I'll take it.
五万里拉   我买了
Well done.
干得不错嘛
When you go for his wallet, he'll catch you by the wrist.
当你要偷他的皮夹时 他就会握住你的手腕
I have done this a few times, Inspector.
督察，这种事我干过好几次
Not like this.
这次不一样
If there isn't a clean print on the bracelet...
如果手镯上没有清晰的指纹
you'll spend the summer in a cell at the Sollicciano.
那么整个夏天 就请你到牢里去乘凉
Give me the bracelet.
把手镯给我
Wash your fucking hands.
先把你的脏手洗干净
He's coming.
他来啦
I got it.
我弄到指纹了
He grabbed me just right.
他正好握住手镯
Tried to hit me in the balls.
居然想攻击我的下体
But he missed.
可惜没成功
Let me help you.
我来帮你
No. Don't.
不要
Sixteen-point match, Mr. Verger.
维杰先生，一共有十六处相符
Bingo.
是他没错
Carlo? Mason?
是卡罗吗？      维杰？
Well, well, well.
都很好
Am I coming to see you? Yes, soon, I hope.
要我去你那儿吗？ 应该快了
But first I need you to pack off the boys.
不过你先把野猪运过来
Now? Yes, I know.
现在？ 是的，我知道
The day you never thought would arrive has.
你以为这一天永远不会来 对不对？
Now, Cordell will fax the veterinary forms...
柯德会直接把兽医表格
directly to Animal and Plant Health...
传真给动植物防疫检疫局
but you need to get the vet affidavits...
但是你必须拿到 撒丁尼亚岛的兽医检验表
How are they?
它们如何？
They are big, Mason, very big.
越长越大，非常庞大
Say again? Yeah, they are big, Mason.
你再说一次 它们长得很大
Really big. Maybe 270 kilos.
大概有270公斤
Oh, wow.
哇！那么大
Can you hear?
你听到了吗？
They sound fantastic.
听起来很强壮
Super.
太好了
The full balance of the money is payable upon receipt of the doctor, alive.
在收到活的汉尼伯医生后 余款就会全数付给你
Of course, you won't have to seize him yourself.
你该不会想自己去抓吧
Rather, just point him out.
只要把他指认出来就行
It's preferable to all concerned if that's the extent of your involvement...
其余的由我们来处理
from this point.
这样对你会比较好
I prefer to stay involved, make sure things go right.
我希望能一直参与下去 好确定不出问题
Professionals will see to that.
那将会由专家来执行
I am a professional.
我就是专家
Did you enjoy the performance, Commendatore?
督察，你对这场演出满意吗？
Very much.
很满意
Allegra, this is Dr. Fell, curator of the Capponi Library.
艾葛莉，这位是费尔博士 卡波尼图书馆的馆长
Signora Pazzi.
帕齐夫人
I'm honored.
很荣幸见到你
Are you from America, Doctor?
你来自美国吗？
Not originally. I've travelled there.
我曾到过美国 但祖籍不是那里
I've always wanted to visit. New England, especially.
我一直想去新英格兰
I've enjoyed many excellent meals there.
那里的食物非常可口
I noticed you wrapped up in the libretto.
我注意到你对歌词很有兴趣
Thought this might amuse you.
相信你会喜欢这个
Dante's first sonnet from La Vita Nuova.
这是但丁新生命中的 第一首十四行诗
It's beautiful.
对，它非常美妙
Rinaldo, look at this. I can see.
帕齐，你来看 我看到了
"Joyous Love seemed to me...
“对我来说喜悦的爱是”
the while he held my heart in his hands...
“当他手中捧着我的心”
and in his arms...
“而在他臂弯中”
my lady lay asleep...
“却是我深爱的女士”
wrapped in a veil."
“正裹着面纱沉睡着”
"He woke her then...
“然后他唤醒她”
and trembling and obedient, she ate that burning heart out of his hand.
“她颤抖而顺从的 吃下他手中灼热的心”
Weeping, I saw him then depart from me."
“我哽咽的看着他逐渐远去”
Dr. Fell, do you believe a man could become so obsessed with a woman...
费尔博士，你相信男人 在第一次和女人相遇后
from a single encounter?
就会迷上她吗？
Could he daily feel a stab of hunger for her...
他因此而寝食难安
and find nourishment in the very sight of her?
只有在见到她后才能平静？
I think so.
我相信
But would she see through the bars of his plight and ache for him?
但是她会看出他的苦境 而深深为他心痛吗？
Please keep that. I couldn't.
这是送给你的 我不能接受
I insist.
我坚持
Good-bye.
再见
Let's get something to eat. Of course.
我们去吃点东西吧 好的
Why not?
好主意
Is that you, Doctor?
医生，这会是你吗？
I'd like to speak with Chief Inspector Rinaldo Pazzi, please.
请帕齐督察接电话
This is Agent Clarice Starling from the American FBI.
我是美国调查局探员史达琳
One moment.
请等一下
FBI. I'm not here.
美国调查局的电话 说我不在
It's Agent Starling from the FBI. How do you do?
我是调查局的史达琳探员 你好？
Actually, I was just leaving for the day.
我现在正准备离开
Can I call you back tomorrow? This won't take long.
明天再和你联络，好吗？ 不会耽误很久
First, thank you for sending us the security tape from the perfume store.
首先，谢谢你们寄给我 香水店的防盗录影带
When I say "you,"I mean your department... Agent Benetti.
我指的是 由班尼帝探员寄来的带子
Is he there? Can I speak with him?
他在吗？我想和他谈谈
I'm sorry. He's gone home. That's all right.
抱歉，他已经走了 那没关系
I should tell you this rather than him anyway.
其实我本就该对你说的
I'm late for an important appointment.
我有个重要约会就要迟到了
The person I'm looking for, Inspector...
我所要寻找的人
who is indeed shown on that tape, is Hannibal Lecter.
就出现在那个录影带里 他的名字是汉尼伯
Who?
谁？
Dr. Hannibal Lecter. You've never heard of him?
汉尼伯医生，你没听过他吗？
I'm not familiar. And the tape confirms...
我不是很清楚 录影带中显示
that he is or was recently in Florence.
他曾在佛罗伦斯出现过
Really? He's a very dangerous man, Inspector.
是吗？ 督察，他非常危险
He's killed 14 people that we know of.
已经杀害十四个人
I really have to go, Miss... Starling.
我得走了，你是… 我叫史达琳
Just another minute.
再给我一分钟
You sure you've never heard of him? No, I haven't.
你确定没听过他吗？ 我确定
Because I'm confused.
那就奇怪了
Someone there has been accessing our private VICAP files on Dr. Lecter...
因为根据资料显示，你们有人 时常使用电脑
with some regularity on your computer.
从我们网站的VICAP档案中 存取汉尼伯医生的资料
Everybody uses everybody's computer here.
警局的电脑是公用的
Maybe one of the detectives on II Mostro...
也许是侦办莫斯楚的警探
was looking at profiles of killers...
上网查看杀人魔的资料
I'm speaking about the computer at your home, sir.
我所说的是你家里的电脑
You're trying to catch him yourself, aren't you? For the reward.
你是不是想自己去捉拿他 好拿悬赏金？
I cannot warn you strongly enough against that.
我必须警告你千万别这么做
He killed three policemen down in Memphis while in custody...
当他在曼非斯被监管时 曾杀了三名警员
tearing the face off one of them, and he will kill you too.
其中之一的脸被他整个撕裂 他也会杀你的
I want him out of Tuscany fast. Believe me...
我要他尽快离开此地 相信我…
he'll be gone from the face of the earth fast.
他很快就会从地球上消失
Feetfirst.
到棺材里去休息
Because of his avarice and his betrayal of the emperor's trust...
由于他的贪婪 背判了信任他的国王
Pier della Vigna was disgraced, blinded and imprisoned.
使得韦格那遭到贬黜 失明和下狱之殃
Dante's pilgrim finds Pier della Vigna on the seventh level of the Inferno...
但丁神曲把他放在地狱篇的 第七层地狱中
and, likeJudas Iscariot, he died by hanging.
就像耶稣的叛徒犹大一样 被处以绞刑
SoJudas and Pier della Vigna are linked in Dante...
由此我们看出是贪婪
by the avarice he saw in them.
使但丁把他们俩连系起来
In fact, avarice and hanging are linked in the medieval mind.
事实上，在中世纪时 贪婪和绞刑常连为一体
This is the earliest known depiction of the Crucifixion...
最早的文献可见于西元400年 被刻在高卢的象牙盒上
carved on an ivory box in Gaul about A.D. 400.
记录着有关耶稣被钉死在 十字架上的故事
It includes the death by hanging ofJudas...
其中包括绞杀犹大
his face upturned to the branch that suspends him.
他的脸孔朝上 面对着吊死他的树枝
Here he is again on the doors of the Benevento Cathedral...
这个在 班尼文多大教堂门上的也是他
this time with his bowels falling out.
不同的是 这里的他内脏外溢
It wasn't easy, but I got this number without tellin'them why...
请你听我说 我好不容易才要到你的号码
Sorry. Not at all. Welcome.
对不起 没关系，欢迎你来
Please join us. Thank you.
请坐   谢谢你
On this plate from the 15th-century edition of the Inferno...
这幅是十五世纪地狱篇的画
Pier della Vigna's body hangs from a bleeding tree.
我们看到韦格那的尸体 挂在流着鲜血的树上
I will not belabor the obvious parallel with Judas Iscariot...
我不想强调他和犹大的相似处
but Dante Alighieri needed no drawn illustration.
因为但丁已经描述得很清楚
It was his genius to make Pier della Vigna, now in hell...
他技巧的表现出 韦格那仍在地狱之中
speak in strained hisses and coughing sibilants...
声嘶力竭的喊叫和挣扎
as though he is hanging still.
就像他仍被吊着一样
Avarice, hanging...
贪婪、绞刑
self-destruction.
自我毁灭
"I make my own home...
“绞架…”
be my gallows."
“就是我的家”
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen, for your kind attention.
今天到此为止 谢谢各位的光临
I'm not a scholar, but I think you've got the job.
我虽然不是学者 但相信你一定能当上馆长
Thank you.
谢谢你
May I buy you a drink? How kind of you. I'd like that.
我能请你去喝杯酒吗？ 这是我的荣幸
I'll be a minute gathering my things.
等我把东西收好就走
Take your time.
慢慢来
Allegra, I'll be home just a little later than I said.
艾葛莉，我会晚点回家
I'm taking Dr. Fell out for a drink.
我和费尔博士去喝杯酒
I can see the people coming out now.
我看到很多人走出来
Yes. Bye, honey. My wife.
很好，等会儿见，是我太太
Of course.
是的
I should have shown them this one.
刚才该给他们看这一张
I can't imagine how I missed it. Remember? I told you about it.
怎么会忘了 记得我曾对你说过吗？
It's a rendering I found in the Capponi Library.
那是我在图书馆里找到的
Can you make it out?
你能看得到吗？
There's a name there...
那里有个名字
the one I told you about.
我曾对你提起过
It's your ancestor, Commendatore...
他就是你的祖先
hanging beneath these very windows.
被吊死在这个窗子下面
Francesco de' Pazzi.
范斯库帕齐
On a related subject, I must confess to you...
另外我想向你坦白
I'm giving very serious thought...
我正在认真的考虑
to eating your wife.
拿你太太当晚餐
If you tell me what I need to know, Commendatore...
如果你能诚实回答我的问题
it might be convenient for me to leave Florence without my meal.
或许到时会放她一马
So I'll ask you the questions, and then we'll see. All right?
我先来问你 然后再做决定，可以吗？
Okay?
好吗？
So.
好
Now, is it Mason Verger you sold me to?
你把我出卖给维杰吗？
No, no.
别挣扎
Blink twice for yes, once for no.
是眨两次眼，不眨一次
Was it Mason Verger you sold me to?
你把我出卖给维杰吗？
Yes, good. Thank you.
是，很好，谢谢你
And are his men waiting for me outside?
他的人在外面等我吗？
Was that a single blink?
那是一下吗？
You're confused.
你搞混了
Please don't be confused, because I may have to fillet Signora Pazzi after all.
别乱搅和，否则我真会把 帕齐夫人的肉片下来吃
Have you told anyone in the questura about me?
你告诉过警局里的人吗？
No, I thought not.
不，我也这么想
Have you told Allegra?
有没有告诉过你太太？
No? Are you sure?
不，你确定
I believe you.
我相信你
Okeydokey, here we go.
好吧，咱们可以开始了
Okay.
好
Your heart is really palpitating.
你的心抖得真厉害
Oh, it's not your heart.
原来不是你的心
Shall I answer it?
我能回答吗？
I've gone above you. I've spoken to your section chief.
我已经向你的局长说过了
Someday you'll thank me. Or you won't. I don't care.
将来你会谢我的 如果恨我，也无所谓
You'll be alive.
至少你还活着
Inspector Pazzi?
帕齐督察？
Is this Clarice?
是史达琳吗？
Hello, Clarice.
哈啰，史达琳
I'm afraid I have bad news for you.
消息恐怕不太好
Is he dead? Did you get my note?
他死了吗？ 你收到我寄给你的信吗？
I hope you like the skin cream. I had it specially made for you.
希望你喜欢那瓶手霜 是我特别替你订制的
Is he dead, Dr. Lecter?
汉尼伯医生，他死了吗？
I would love nothing more in this world than to be able to chat with you.
你要知道，我最喜欢和你聊天
Unfortunately, you've caught me at an awkward moment.
可惜现在实在不方便
Please forgive me.
请原谅我
See you around.
再见
An old friend.
是个老朋友
Okay, hold on.
好，别动
Here we go.
咱们走吧
I'll go around back! Kill him if you have to!
我走后门，必要时杀了他
What's it to be?
你喜欢哪样？
Bowels in or bowels out...
是内脏在里面，还是…
likeJudas?
像犹大一样流得满地都是
Are you confused?
难道这又困扰你吗？
I'll decide for you, if you'll permit me.
那就由我来决定吧
Good evening.
晚安
Cordell...
柯德
to you...
依你看…
does that look like a wave good-bye...
他的招手是表示再会呢
or hello?
还是表示哈啰
So, what do you think?
你是怎么想？
Does Lecter want to fuck her or kill her or eat her or what?
到底汉尼伯是想和她睡觉 杀她还是吃她呢？
Probably all three.
也许三者都是
Though I wouldn't want to predict in what order.
只是不知道是什么顺序
Here's what I think.
这是我的想法
No matter how Barney might want to romanticize it...
不管巴尼加入多少浪漫的情节
and make it Beauty and the Beast...
把他们描述得像美女与野兽一般
Lecter's object, as I know from personal experience...
依我以前的经验来看
has always been...
汉尼伯的目的永远是
degradation...
让人逐渐崩溃
and suffering.
并且受尽痛苦
Get this damn thing off me. I can't breathe in this thing.
把这该死的面具拿走 搞得我不能呼吸
He comes in the guise of a mentor...
他常以良师益友的身份出现
as he did with me and her.
就像当初他对我和她一样
But it's distress that excites him.
痛苦会使他兴奋
To draw him...
为了要引出他来
she needs to be distressed.
就必须要让她痛苦
To make her attractive to him, let him see her distressed.
因为 当他看到她痛苦时就会现身
Let the damage he sees...
我要他在看到她的痛苦后
suggest the damage he could do.
而忍不住去伤害她
When the fox hears the rabbit scream, he comes a-runnin'.
就像狐狸听到兔子悲鸣时 会跑过去吃掉它
But not to help.
而不会去帮助它
I don't understand.
可是我不懂
There's nothing to understand, Paul.
保罗，你不需要懂
All you have to understand is what it's worth to you.
只要知道你能拿不少钱就行了
No, no, I don't understand why she didn't turn this over.
不是，我不懂 以她诚实的个性
I mean, she's such a straight arrow.
她应该会把它交出来的
She didn't turn it over because she didn't receive it.
她没交出来，是因为没收到
She didn't receive it because it was never sent.
她没收到，是因为没寄给她
It was never sent because Lecter didn't write it.
没寄给她，是因为汉尼伯没写
He didn't write it because I did.
他没写，是因为那是我写的
So, what do you think?
你认为如何？
You'd have been better off if you'd never got her out of trouble.
我觉得你最好别再帮她
Oh, woulda, shoulda, coulda. I meant, what do you think about the money?
你管得也太多了 我是问你要多少钱？
Five.
五
Let's just toss it off, like "five."
让我们为这个五干一杯
Let's say it with the respect it deserves.
你最好说清楚到底要多少
Five hundred thousand dollars.
我是说五十万
That's better, but not much.
很好，不多嘛
Now, will it work? It'll work.
能成功吗？      绝对可以
It won't be pretty.
可惜不会很好看
What ever is?
那没关系
Cocksucker.
白痴
Never seen this before in my life.
我从没见过这东西
Then how do you account for its being found in your office, your basement?
那为什么会在地下室 你的办公室里找到呢？
How do you want me to answer that, Mr. Krendler?
你要我怎么回答
What possible reason might I have to withhold it?
我根本没必要把它藏起来
Perhaps because of the nature of its content.
或许是因为它的内容
Reads to me like a love letter.
念起来倒像封情书
Has it been tested for prints? No prints on it. None on the last one.
有没有查过指纹 没有指纹
Handwriting analysis?
笔迹分析呢？
It's because you're the answer to Samson's riddle.
“因为你就是参孙之谜”
You are the honey in the lion."
“你是狮子里的蜜糖”
Sounds like him to me.
很像他
Do you mean, like a homosexual? Like a nut with a crush.
你是说像同性恋？ 我说像那个迷恋你的傻瓜
Director Noonan, I need to say something...
执政官诺门，我想说点…
Agent Starling, I am placing you on administrative leave...
史达琳探员 我命令你暂时停职
till document analysis tells me unequivocally a mistake's been made.
直到文件的分析 证明我们做出错误的决定为止
In the meantime, you remain eligible for insurance and medical benefits.
在此期间 你仍能享用医疗保险
Surrender your weapons and your identification to Agent Pearsall.
把你的武器 和证件交给柏塞探员
I want to say something. I think I'm entitled.
我有权力表达自己的想法
Go ahead.
请讲
I think Mr. Mason Verger is trying to capture Dr. Lecter...
我认为 维杰先生为了私人恩怨
for the purposes of personal revenge.
想要捉住汉尼伯医师
I think Mr. Krendler is in collusion with him...
我认为保罗先生和他勾结
and wants the FBI's efforts against Dr. Lecter to work for Mr. Verger.
利用调查局的资源 去帮助维杰先生
I think Mr. Krendler is being paid to do this.
我更认为保罗先生已被人收买
Lucky you're not sworn here today. Swear me! You swear too!
好在你今天没有发誓 少吓我，你去发誓呀！
Clarice, if the evidence is lacking...
史达琳，如果证据不足
you'll be entitled to full reinstatement without prejudice...
你就能立即复职
if you don't do or say anything in the meantime...
但是你若采取不合作的态度
that would make that impossible.
那就没希望了
Relieved of field duty pending an internal investigation...
史达琳探员在调查局任职十年
Special Agent Clarice Starling, a ten-year veteran on the Bureau...
如今却被解除职务 等待内部调查
began her career with an assignment...
她的事业始于
to interview lethal madman Hannibal Lecter.
与致命狂人汉尼伯的会晤
Earlier, we heard comments from Justice Department spokesman Paul Krendler.
早先，我们听到 司法部发言人保罗的评论
Can you comment on theJustice Department's decision this morning?
请你评论一下
The FBI and theJustice Department are looking very carefully into the charges.
调查局和司法部 都非常小心的处理此事
And, yes, they are extremely serious.
而且态度非常认真
I'd like to add a personal note, though.
我想加点自己的想法
Starling's one of our best agents. No, no, no, stay.
史达琳是我们最好的探员之一 不，你留下来
I would be very surprised if these accusations turn out to be true.
我不相信这些控诉会成立
Is theJustice Department and FBI united in this decision?
难道司法部和调查局 真的采取同一步调吗？
It's much too soon to condemn her...
现在还太早替她做结论
Good boy.
乖狗
I think she's nice.
我觉得她很好
She's always been nice to me. Polite.
她对我一直很好，很有礼貌
Don't you think?
难道你不同意
Do you know what a roller pigeon is, Barney?
巴尼，你知道鹞鸽是什么吗？
Roller pigeons climb high and fast...
鹞鸽喜欢飞得很高很快
then roll over and fall just as fast towards the Earth.
然后翻着筋斗快速冲向地面
There are shallow rollers and there are deep rollers...
鹞鸽又分成肤浅和深沉两种
but you can't breed two deep rollers, or their young, their offspring...
但是当两个深沉的鹞鸽结合时
will roll all the way down, hit and die.
它们的后代 往往会俯冲撞地而死
Agent Starling is a deep roller.
史达琳探员是只深沉的鹞鸽
Let's hope one of her parents was not.
只希望她父母中 有一个是肤浅的鹞鸽
The power in that battery is low, Clarice.
史达琳，电话的电池快用完了
I would've changed it, but I didn't want to wake you.
为了不吵醒你，我没换
Use the one in the charger. Hopefully, the light on it is green by now.
你可以用充电器里的电池 但愿现在已经充好电了
Because this is gonna be a long call and I can't let you off...
因为这通电话会很长 而我又不愿意中途被切断
because even though you've been stripped of your duties...
更因为 他们虽然剥夺了你的职责
I know you won't abandon them... you'll try to put on a trace.
但你一定会继续调查下去 绝不放弃
So we'll disconnect long enough for you to exchange the battery in the phone...
所以我们先挂断电话 好让你换电池
Shall we say, three seconds?
三秒钟够吗？
Are you ready? Yes.
准备好了吗？      好了
Go.
开始
Very good. Thank you.
很好      谢谢你
Remember, Clarice, if you get caught with a concealed, unlicensed firearm...
在哥伦比亚区 被抓到无照带枪
in the District of Columbia, the penalty is very stiff.
惩罚相当严重
But bring the guns if you have to. Now get in your car.
不过如果你坚持那就带吧 现在到车里去
The reason we're doing it like this, Clarice...
我之所以这么做
is because I like to watch you as we speak, with your eyes open.
是因为当我们谈话时 我希望你是清醒的
No, it does not excite me. It pleases me.
别紧张，那不会使我兴奋 只会让我高兴而已
You have very shapely feet.
你的脚形很美
Where are we now? Call it out.
你现在在哪里？把街名念出来
Massachusetts Avenue.
麻萨诸塞街
Take it.
到麻萨诸塞街去
I thought, to begin with, you might tell me how you're feeling.
我们就拿你的感受做开场吧
About what?
那方面的？
The masters you serve and how they've treated you.
例如你雇主如何对待你
Your career, such as it is.
还有你的职业
Your life, Clarice.
甚至你的生命…等等
I thought we might talk about yours.
我以为会谈你的事
What's the next cross street? Capitol Street.
下面的横街叫什么？ 国会街
In two blocks, make a left into Union Station. Park.
你在第二条街左转 把车停到火车站去
My life? What is there to say about mine?
我的生命？那有什么好谈
I have been in a state of hibernation for some time...
我已冬眠了一段日子
a little inactive.
乏善可陈
But now I'm back home and I'm very happy...
可是现在我回来了 既快乐又健康
You. It's you I'm worried about. I'm fine.
倒是你让我很操心 我很好
No, you're certainly not fine, Clarice.
不，你一点也不好
You fell in love with the Bureau, the institution...
你把自己奉献给调查局
only to discover, after giving it everything you've got...
然而在付出一切之后
that it does not love you back...
却发现他们并不喜欢你
that, in fact, it resents you.
这点让你愤愤不平
It resents you more than the husband and children you gave up to it.
比放弃丈夫和孩子还要愤怒
Why is that, do you think? Why are you so resented?
为什么？为什么你会这么愤怒
Tell me. Tell you?
你告诉我   我告诉你？
God bless you.
上帝会保佑你
Well, isn't it clear?
你难道还看不出来
You serve the idea of order, Clarice.
你听命行事
They don't.
他们不是
You believe in the oath you took.
你遵守宣誓
You feel it is your duty to protect the sheep. They don't.
你觉得保护弱小是你的责任 他们不是
They don't like you because you're not like them.
因为你的不同 所以他们不喜欢你
They hate you and envy you.
他们对你又妒又恨
They are weak, unruly and believe in nothing.
他们懦弱、任性、又无法无天
Mason Verger wants to kill you, Dr. Lecter.
汉尼伯医生，维杰要杀你
Turn yourself in to me, and I promise no one will hurt you.
向我投降 我保证没人会伤害你
Will you stay with me in my prison cell and hold my hand, Clarice?
你会握着我的手 和我一起待在监狱里吗？
We could have some fun.
那样一定很有意思
No, Mason Verger does not want to kill me any more than I want to kill him.
你错了，其实我更想杀维杰
He just wants to see me suffer in some unimaginable way.
他只想用 不可思议的方法来折磨我
He is rather twisted, you know.
是个无可救药的疯子
Have you had the pleasure of meeting him?
你见过他吗？
Face-to-face, so to speak?
面对面？
Yes.
是的
Attractive, isn't he? Dr. Lecter?
他是不是很引人注意？ 汉尼伯医生
Okay, back to you.
好，再回来谈你
I want to know what it is you think you will do...
如今所有你关心的东西 全被他们拿走了
I don't know, Dr. Lecter.
我不知道
Clarice, do you think you'll work as a chambermaid...
你能像你妈妈一样
at a motel on Route 66...
到汽车旅馆里去
just like your mommy?
当打扫女工吗？
What are you thinking now?
你在想什么？
Are you paying attention to me, ex-Special Agent Starling?
卸任的史达琳探员 你在听我说话吗？
Are you, by any chance, trying to trace my whereabouts?
还是想找出我的藏身处
I'm being followed, Dr. Lecter. I know. I've seen them.
汉尼伯医生，我被跟踪了 我已经看到他们
And now you're in a real dilemma, aren't you?
你现在真是左右为难
Do you continue to try to find me, knowing that you are leading them to me?
明知会引导他们找到我 难道你还要继续找吗？
Do you have so much faith in your abilities that you honestly believe...
还是你认为，自己真有能力
you can somehow simultaneously arrest me and them?
能同时逮捕我们双方
It could get very messy, Clarice, like the fish market.
不过结果可能会和 鲜鱼市场一样糟糕
What if I did it for you? Did what?
让我来替你做，如何？ 做什么？
Harmed them, Clarice, the ones who have harmed you.
伤害那些伤害过你的人
What if I made them scream apologies?
叫他们来求你的原谅
No, I shouldn't even say it...
不，我真不该说
because you'll feel, with your perfect grasp of right and wrong...
因为若以你的是非标准来衡量
that you were somehow accompli.
恐怕会认为自己也是共犯
Don't help me.
别帮我
No, of course not. Forget I said it.
当然不会，忘了我所说的
Clarice, you were very, very warm.
你很接近目标
You were so close.
非常接近
And now you're getting colder again.
现在又偏了
Yeah, warmer again.
对，就是这儿
Well, I think I've been generous enough with you and the clues.
好啦，给你的提示已经够多了
You're on your own now, Clarice. Dr. Lecter.
你自己去找吧 汉尼伯医生
Hope you like them, Clarice. Ta-ta.
希望你喜欢它们，回见
Go.
放进去
Get out of the way!
别挡住我！
I know the first thing a hysteric says is, "I am not a hysteric"...
我知道歇斯底里人的第一句话 是“我没有歇斯底里”
but I am not a hysteric. I am calm.
但是我很镇静没有歇斯底里
I'll ask you one time. Think before you answer.
我再问你一次，先想过再回答
Think about every good thing you ever did.
想想你以前的优良事迹
Think about what you swore.
想想你的宣誓
Two men in a van, a third driving, another man down.
有两个人在货车里 第三个开车，另一个倒地不起
They put him in the back. I think it was Lecter.
他们把他放在后面 我想是汉尼伯
I gave you a license, and I'm reporting it to you again in front of witnesses.
我给你车牌号码，并且会在 目击者面前再向你报告一次
All right.
好吧
I'll go with it as a kidnapping.
我将以绑架来处理
I'll send someone with the local authorities...
我会派人和当地警员前往
if they'll let us on the property without a warrant.
希望他们 不会要我们出示搜索状
I should go. You could deputize me. No. You're not going.
我也去，你可以指定我为代表 不行，你不能去
You're going home, where you'll wait for me to call...
你该回家等我电话
and tell you what, if anything, we've found.
如有发现我会马上告诉你
Thank Mr. Verger for letting us look around. Sorry if we inconvenienced him.
谢谢维杰先生让我们查看 若有打扰的地方请原谅
He's always happy to see you.
放心，他随时都欢迎你们
Phone.
我要打电话
What number, please?
什么号码
Carlo.
接卡罗
Give me one.
给我一杯
How is he? Sleeping.
他怎么样？   在睡觉
Bring him home.
把他带回家吧
You've reached Clarice Starling. Please leave a message.
这是史达琳，请留话
Pick up, Starling.
史达琳，接电话
There was nothing out there.
那里一切正常
I'm gonna say it again, in case you didn't hear me.
我再重复一遍
You are not a law officer while you're on suspension. You'reJoe Blow.
当你被停职时，就是普通百姓 而不是执法警官
Hope for your sake you're in the bathroom.
为了你好，希望你正在洗澡
Hylochoerus...
巨大的…
meinertzhageni.
丛林猪
Ring any bells from high school biology, Doctor?
高中的生物学中曾经提过 你还记得吗？
No?
不记得了？
Well, I could list its most conspicuous features...
让我把它的特征告诉你
if that would help jog the memory.
或许会唤起你的记忆
Three pairs of incisors...
有三对门牙
one pair of elongated canines...
一对延长犬齿
three pairs of molars...
三对臼齿
four pairs of premolars...
四对前臼齿
upper and lower...
上下加起来
for a total of 44 teeth.
一共四十四颗牙
The meal will begin with an hors d'oeuvres tartare...
它们正餐前的开胃菜
your feet.
就是生吃人脚
The main course... the rest of you...
主菜当然是少了一双脚的你
won't be served until seven hours later.
不过得在七个钟头后才开饭
But during that time...
在那段时间里
you'll be able to enjoy the effects of the consumed appetizer...
我会为你全身会打满点滴
with a full-bodied saline drip.
好让你能清醒的感觉到 被生吃的痛楚
I guess you wish now...
我打赌你正在想
you'd fed the rest of me to the dogs.
当初真该把我喂狗吃
No, Mason.
不会的
No, I much prefer you the way you are.
我喜欢你现在这样
So...
那么…
dinner at 8:00.
晚餐就订在八点
You will stay for the evening's entertainment...
柯德，今晚的娱乐活动
won't you, Cordell?
你会参加吧？
If it's all right with you...
如果你不介意
I think I'd rather not.
我宁可不想参加
Rather not...
是宁可不
or will not?
还是宁愿不？
Your little brother must smell almost as badly as you do by now.
你弟弟现在的味道 一定和你一样难闻
Hold it! Hands where I can see 'em!
不准动，手举起来
Quiet!
闭嘴
What was that?
那是什么声音？
Cordell, quickly!
柯德，快一点
Get on your stomach.
趴下来
Good evening, Clarice.
史达琳，晚安
Just like old times. Shut up.
像又回到往日一样 闭嘴
Can you walk? I can try.
你能走吗？   我会尽力
You look well.
你看起来不错
I'm gonna cut you loose.
现在给你松绑
If you touch me, I'll shoot you.
别碰我，否则我马上开枪
Understood. Do right and you'll live through this.
我了解 不捣蛋你就能活着出去
Spoken like a true Protestant. Better hurry.
语气和新教徒一样，最好快点
Things might go faster if you hand me the knife.
把刀给我会快一点
There was a third in the loft.
第三个人在阁楼上
No, Clarice. Behind me.
不，是我后面
Cordell, shoot him! Get the gun and shoot him!
柯德，杀他 拿起枪，把他杀了
Go into the pen? Yes!
到围栏里去   当然！
No. I'm staying out of this.
不，我不要牵扯进去
You're involved, is what you are, in all of it. Now do it!
不管怎样 你已经扯进来了，快去
No. Yes!
不      你快去！
Hey, Cordell, why don't you push him in?
柯德，干脆把他推进去
You can always say it was me.
到时推到我头上就行了
Mary, it's me.
玛莉，是我
I decided to take off early. I'll be at my lake house all weekend.
我决定提前下班 周末到湖边去住
I don't want any calls forwarded either. Do you understand?
别把电话接过去 你听清楚了吗？
Whoever it is, they can all wait. Okay?
不管谁都让他们等，懂吗？
Listen, it's 4th ofJuly, for Christ's sake. Thank you.
拜托这是国庆假日呀，谢谢你
What the fuck?
怎么搞的？
Good. You brought the wine.
很好，你带酒来了
One time I bet a friend I could hold a lit firecracker in my hand...
有一次我手里拿着 点燃的爆竹和朋友打赌
longer than he could.
赌我能拿得比他久
Can I guess?
你猜结果如何？
You lost the bet, and he lost a finger. Am I right?
你输了赌注 他丢了手指头，对不对？
This won't hurt a bit.
放心，不会痛的
Are we expecting guests?
有客人要来吗？
We've traced your call and units will be there in about ten minutes.
我们已经追踪到电话 警方在十分钟内会到达
If you can do it safely, just get out of the house.
如果你能到屋外去最好
Otherwise, stay on the phone with me.
否则就继续和我通话
Ma'am?
小姐？
Are you there? Ma'am?
小姐，你仍在线上吗？
You need to make sure they feel welcome.
你必须让客人觉得温暖
Are those shallots? And caper berries.
那是冬葱吗？ 还有续随子香料
That butter smells wonderful.
奶油闻起来好香
You feeling hungry, Paul?
保罗，你饿了吗？
Very.
好饿
What's the main course?
主菜是什么？
You should never ask. It spoils the surprise.
你不该问，那样就没有惊喜了
Clarice, what are you doing up? You should be resting. Get back to bed.
史达琳，你起来干什么？ 你应该休息，快回床上去
I'm hungry.
我饿了
Hello, Paul. Paul, don't be rude.
哈啰，保罗 保罗，要有礼貌
Say, "Hello, Agent Starling."
说“哈啰，史达琳探员”
Hello, Agent Starling.
哈啰，史达琳探员
I always wanted to watch you eat.
我一直想看你吃饭
What have you got in your hand? Something to bash me on the head with?
你手里拿着什么 是想拿来砸我的头吗？
Put it on the table.
把它放在桌子上
Good girl.
乖孩子
Hey. That's mine.
嘿，那是我的
Now sit down.
坐下来
Hey, Clarice, love the dress.
史达琳，我喜欢你的衣服
It's beautiful.
很漂亮
What do you think, Paul? Nice.
保罗，你说呢？   好
Why don't you say grace, Paul?
保罗 由你来说饭前祈祷文好吗？
Me? Yeah.
我？   是的
Grace? Sure.
祈祷文？      没错
Okay.
好
Bow your head.
把头低下来
Father, we thank Thee for Thy blessings...
天父，感谢你赐给我们食物
and dedicate them to Thy mercy...
以及你对他们的慈悲
We are about to receive...
我们将要接受圣餐
Forgive us all...
请饶恕我们大家
even white trash like Starling here...
也饶恕史达琳这种穷白鬼
and bring her into my service, amen.
并让她替我服务，阿门
I have to tell you, Paul, even the Apostle Paul couldn't have done better.
我必须告诉你，即使是基督的 门徒保罗，说得也没你好
He hated women too.
他也讨厌女人
May I have some wine, please? I don't think that's a good idea.
我能喝点酒吗？ 恐怕不好
Not with the morphine.
你身上还有吗啡
I think you should eat some broth. Okay?
你最好喝点汤
By the way, that was a job offering I worked into the blessing.
顺便告诉你 祈祷文里有你的工作机会
I'm going to Congress, you know.
因为我想进军众议院
Are you?
是吗？
Come around campaign headquarters.
到我的竞选总部来
You could be an office girl. Can you type and file?
你可以做办公小姐 你会打字和存档吗？
Can you take dictation? Take this down.
会速记吗？把这个记下来
Washington is full of corn pone, country pussy.
华盛顿充满了种田的乡下女人
I took it down. You said it already.
已经记下来，你早先说过了
Paul, now you're being rude, and I hate rude people.
保罗，你变得很无礼 我讨厌无礼的家伙
Drink your broth like a good boy. Come on. Sip.
乖孩子，先喝汤 来，吸一口
Good.
很好
It's not very good, buddy.
老兄呀，实在不好喝
I admit I added something to yours. Perhaps it's clashing with the cumin.
我加了点其他作料 可能和茴香的香味不调合
But I assure you, the next course is to die for.
但是保证你会爱死下道菜
Come on, Clarice.
别这样
That's a good girl.
这才乖
Good.
很好
Dr. Lecter.
汉尼伯医生
You see, the brain itself feels no pain, Clarice, if that concerns you.
你不用担心 其实脑本身没有痛楚感
For example, Paul won't miss this little piece here...
例如这是前头叶 就算保罗少了它也没有关系
which they say is the seat of good manners.
因为据说 它能使人有良好的态度
Your profile at the border stations has five features.
你的档案在边界警局中 有五个重点
I'll trade you. Trade?
我和你交换   交换？
Stop, and I'll tell you what they are. How does that word taste to you?
放了他，我就告诉你那些资料 你对交换两个字有什么感觉
Cheap and metallic, like sucking on a greasy coin?
又冷又硬 就像在啜一枚油腻的硬币似的
Who's Clarice? Agent Starling, Paul.
谁是克莉丝？ 就是史达琳探员
If you can't keep up with the conversation, try not to join in at all.
如果你跟不上就别打岔
Paul, I'm Starling.
保罗，我就是史达琳
See...
你看…
here...
就在这里…
right here's the sac that contains the brain.
脑子就在这个液囊之中
I would really like some wine.
我真的需要喝点酒
That smells great. Yes.
好好闻哟      没错
There. Like to try a little piece?
好了，要试一小块吗？
I would really like some wine...
我是真的要喝点酒
It is good.
很好吃
All right. Just a little.
好，不过只能喝一点
Okay?
喝吧
Given the chance, you would deny me my life, wouldn't you?
只要有机会 你连我的命都会要，对不对？
Not your life.
不是你的命
My freedom, just that. You'd take that from me.
那是自由啰 你要把我的自由拿走
And if you did, would they have you back, do you think?
就算你这么做 他们会要你回去吗？
The FBI?
我是说调查局
Those people you despise almost as much as they despise you?
你蔑视的人同样也轻视你
Will they give you a medal, Clarice, do you think?
你想他们会给你奖章吗？
Would you have it professionally framed and hang it on your wall to look at...
然后你把它装框挂在墙上
and remind you of your courage and incorruptibility?
每天看着它，提醒自己 有多勇敢和清廉吗？
All you would need for that, Clarice, is a mirror.
果真如此，一面镜子就够了
I have plans for that smart mouth. I'm never gonna hire you now.
伶牙俐齿的人我另有用处 我永远不会再雇用你
If you can't be polite to our guests...
如果对客人不礼貌
you have to sit at the kiddies' table.
就要到小孩桌去坐
Don't get up, Clarice.
史达琳，你别起来
Paul will help me clear and make the coffee.
保罗会帮我收拾和煮咖啡
Just think about what I said, Clarice.
你仔细想想我说的话
Coffee.
咖啡
I came halfway around the world...
我绕了半个地球
to watch you run, Clarice.
就为了看你如何释放自己
Let me run, huh?
释放我，好吗？
Tell me, Clarice, would you ever say to me...
史达琳 会不会有一天你对我说…
"Stop.
“别这么做”
If you loved me, you'd stop"?
“如果爱我，就别这么做”
Not in a thousand years.
永远不会
That's my girl.
我就欣赏你这点
Now, that's really interesting, Clarice...
史达琳，我必须承认你不简单
and I'm really pressed for time.
而我的时间又很紧迫
So where's the key?
告诉我钥匙在哪里
Where's the key?
钥匙呢？
Okay.
好
Above...
你要切在…
or below the wrist...
手腕的上面…
Clarice?
还是下面？
This is really gonna hurt.
这次绝对会很疼
Show me your hands!
把手举起来
Identify yourself!
说明你的身份
I'm Clarice Starling!
我是克莉丝史达琳
FBI!
调查局探员
Hi.
嗨   嗨
What's that?
那是什么？
That's caviar.
那是鱼子酱
What are those? These are figs.
那些呢？      无花果
And that?
那个呢？
This?
这个吗？
That I don't think you would like.
我想你不会喜欢
It looks good. Oh, it is good.
看起来很好吃 是很好吃
Can I have some?
我能尝尝吗？
You're a very unusual boy, aren't you?
你是个很奇怪的孩子
I couldn't eat what they gave me. Nor should you. It isn't even food...
我不喜欢吃他们给我的食物
So, which would you like to try?
那么你想吃哪一种？
Well, I suppose it's all right.
我想应该没关系吧
After all, as your mother tells you, and my mother certainly told me...
毕竟 你我的妈妈都曾说过这句话
"It is important," she always used to say...
我记得她常说“重要的是…”
"always to try new things."
“要不断尝试不同的东西”
Open up.
嘴张开